DAVID SHERIDAN

PROFILE



21 Archers Wood Green, Archers Wood, Delgany, Co. Wicklow

davidsheridandsgn@gmail.com D.O.B. 05/09/1991 0851337449 I'm a senior digital product designer who aims to create engaging & relevant solutions to complex design challenges.

Experienced in designing & developing user–centred solutions across web & mobile applications, in both in–house & agency environments alongside teams of designers, developers & product managers.

Education

2017-2019

MSc in User Experience Design from IADT.

2018

- Mark Strong's management training course.
- Agile Innovation's team primer in agile & scrum course.
- Team Treehouse's beginner Javascript course.

2011-2015

 B.A. Honours degree in Visual Communications from IADT.

2010-2011

 FETAC Art Foundation Course from Stillorgan College of Further Education.

EXPERIENCE

Nory Al

Senior Digital Product Designer July 2024 – April 2024

Responsible for leading the product & design direction of Nory's Inventory Management offering. This is used by restaurants to manage their inventory using AI, ensuring they minimize their overheads while maximising their profit margins.

This work is done in collaboration with the CEO, head of design, engineering team lead & a team of developers across both our desktop & mobile platforms.

Responsibilities include:

- Competitor analysis.
- Remote & in-person user research.
- Facilitating workshops with key stakeholders.
- Developing & maintaining team backlog.

- Planning team quarterly roadmap alongside CEO, Head of Design & engineering team lead.
- Designing user journeys & wireframes.
- Creating prototypes in Figma.
- UI design.
- Information architecture design.
- Collaborating with developers to implement designs
- Implementing Mixpanel dashboards to monitor the impact of new releases.
- Presenting new releases to internal stakeholders at weekly company call.
- Facilitating educational workshops for new hires.
- Sharing team lead responsibilities alongside the principle engineer while recruiting new team lead.
- Supporting the sales team on sales calls.

DAVID SHERIDAN

EXPERIENCE (CONTINUED)

Glofox

Senior Digital Product Designer November 2020 – July 2023

Responsible for leading the design direction of Glofox Services, used by clients to set up & sell services such as memberships to their customers. This work is done in collaboration with the head of design, multiple product managers, designers, engineering team leads & teams of developers across both our desktop & mobile platforms.

Responsibilities include:

- Mentoring designers in user research & communication skills.
- Standardising the company's research principles & practices alongside the head of design.
- Contributing design components & updates to the design system.

- Participating in the hiring process of potential candidates alongside the head of design.
- Helping to onboard new designers.
- Competitor analysis.
- Heuristic analysis.
- Remote & in-person user research.
- Working with product managers & engineering teams to plan out projects through user story mapping.
- Designing user journeys & wireframes.
- Information architecture design.
- Creating prototypes in Figma and Protopie.
- UI design.
- Collaborating with developers to implement designs.
- Regularly presenting work to the company at bi-weekly all hands.

Storyful

Digital Product Designer October 2017 – May 2019 Senior Digital Product Designer June 2019 – November 2020

Responsible for designing & improving the user experience of an internal web-based application used by teams of journalists & analysts to search & analyse social media data. This is done within a scrum team of developers & a product owner.

Other responsibilities include leading research initiatives & the design direction of the design system alongside a leadership panel containing the lead designer & lead developers.

Responsibilities include:

- Mentoring designers in user research & interaction design.
- Leading the user research guild & the company's customer research initiative.

- Leading the design direction & governance structure of the design system alongside the lead designer & lead developers.
- Competitor analysis.
- Remote & in-person user research.
- Working with the product owner to define the quarterly product roadmap.
- Designing user journeys & wireframes.
- Heuristic analysis.
- Creating prototypes in InVision.
- UI design.
- Collaborating with developers to implement designs.
- Information architecture design.
- Communicating design updates through presentations
 & the company blog.

DAVID SHERIDAN

EXPERIENCE (CONTINUED)

Isobar

User Experience Designer August 2016 – October 2017

Responsible for designing & improving the user experience of new & existing websites within a team of designers & developers.

PatientBuddy

Digital Product Designer July 2015 – July 2016

Responsible for designing web & mobile applications for medical conditions ranging from prostate cancer to kidney transplants, within an in-house team of designers & developers.

Maithú IT Solutions

Digital Product Designer July 2015 – July 2016

Responsible for designing improvements & implementing front end updates for the in–house medical app 'Medical E-Guides' within a team of designers & developers.

PUBLICATIONS

#AreYouFollowingMe?

An Analysis of UI Design & User Behaviour in Social Media

The Development of Trust & Cognitive Load in Human-Automation Interaction

Evaluating the Impact of Visualisation Techniques on Results of Automated Desktop Applications.

TALKS

Engineering Management Ireland

January 2020

Creating a Research Guild to Build Leadership Skills
Gave a talk that discussed my personal experiences of
developing leadership skills through creating a
research guild, with recommendations given.

UXDX Community Meetup

May 2020

Utilising Guilds to Develop a Culture of Research
Delivered a talk that discussed the development of
a research culture & practices within an Agile Scrum
environment through the development of a research guild.
Examples & successful milestones were discussed with
recommendations given.